# Tomiwa Kukoyi



tomiwakukoyi07@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/oluwatomiwakukovi07



+2347083325053



https://github.com/Tomiwakukoyi

### Summary

Well detailed, creative, skilled and hardworking Frontend Developer with over four years of experience in using some of the best Frontend technologies to create pixel perfect frontend applications. Experienced in bringing website designs to life in real time with the modern Frontend technology, writing clean and readable code with proper folder structure and troubleshooting. Excellent team player always ready to help and find solutions to problems. Always eager to deliver the best for the company

## **Professional Experience**

# **Vue JS Developer**

Mein Sherpa

Main tools used - Vue JS, Tailwind CSS, Flowbite, CSS, XAMPP, PHP, Git and GitHub

I worked as a frontend developer using Vue JS as the main Frontend tool and Tailwind CSS as the main styling tool on this job.

- I had to quickly learn Vue JS while working on this job as my main tool was React JS
- I was able to deliver my work before deadlines despite me just learning the technology
- I took advantage of having team members and asked questions whenever I got stuck
- I worked with the backend developer to implement my Frontend designs and ensure they were displaying data gotten from the backend
- I ensured to write readable and clean code while my commit messages were also written in a manner that other team members can easily understand what exactly was going on.
- I also encountered lots of errors while working but I was always able to find a way out of them quickly
- I also ensured to have a very good rapport with my team so that we made good progress on features we needed to implement
- I worked as an unsupervised Frontend developer

# React JS Developer – Disney+ (Clone)

Oct 2022- Jan 2023

Feb 2023 - Present

#### Main tools used - React JS, Firebase, Redux Toolkit, Styled-Components

Implemented all Ecommerce store features. Implemented a product page, add to cart and checkout features, editing and removing items from the cart, adding multiple quantities of the same item. Ensured clean and readable code and proper folder structure throughout this project.

- I used Sanity for the content management and backend
- Context API was used for the state management of this project
- Took advantage of the excellent SSR feature of Next JS to ensure navigation through pages are at super
- I used the updated version of Next JS, Sanity and their features
- I used Next JS functions like getServerSideProps and getStaticProps among other hooks provided by Next
- Vanilla CSS was used for the styling throughout the project by running all the styles through the global.css
- The web app is also fully mobile responsive
- I used external react libraries like React-icons and react-hot-toast at various points during this project
- I also switched to Yarn from NPM after the project to fix some dependency issues before deploying the website

React Developer April 2022 - Oct 2022

**Linux Jobber (Intern)** 

#### Main tools used - React JS, Tailwind CSS, Styled Components, Vanilla CSS, API

Worked on various projects and provided solutions to problems. Implemented a login and signup simulation. Implemented forms with modern features like range slider and drag-n-drop. Worked with a teammate to implement various functionalities and delivered before schedule. Communicated with other interns to provide solution to problems they faced and also get solutions to some of my problems.

- I used React best practices in implementing a signup feature that took in users' information and then output it like a result
- -During the task above, I implemented a range slider feature for some of the required information
- I retrieved data from an API and displayed it in one of the tasks required of me
- In one of the tasks given to create a signup/login and then implement a task tracker which then led to me implementing a drag and drop feature using an external react library
- I used different styling technologies like tailwind CSS, styled-components and vanilla CSS I also implemented a modern dynamic form I also worked with other interns whenever I had difficulty, I asked lots of questions and it made my work faster

# Next JS Developer – E-commerce Store Optimind

Nov 2021 - Feb 2022

Main tools used - Next JS, Sanity, Context API, CSS

Implemented a product page, add to cart and checkout features, editing and removing items from the cart, adding multiple quantities of the same item. Ensured clean and readable code and proper folder structure throughout this project.

- I used FEBSanity for the content management and backend
- Context API was used for the state management of this project
- Took advantage of the excellent SSR feature of Next JS for navigation through pages
- I used the updated version of Next JS, Sanity and their features
- I used Next JS functions like getServerSideProps and getStaticProps
- Vanilla CSS was used for the styling throughout the project by running all the styles through the global.css
- The web app is also fully mobile responsive
- I used external react libraries like React-icons and react-hot-toast at various points during this project
- I also switched to Yarn from NPM after the project to fix some dependency issues before deploying the website

#### React Developer - Musica

Mar 2021 – Aug 2021

**Freelance Contract** 

Main tools used - React JS, Tailwind CSS, SCSS, Vanilla CSS, Rapid API

Implemented just the UI of this website.

- Musica is a music streaming app I built with React JS
- I built just the UI with few functionalities
- I ensured to maintain proper and easy to understand folder structure• I used props to pass data from components to components including images
- I used React- Router for routing through the pages of this App.
- I made use of Styled-components, Tailwind CSS and vanilla CSS and SCSS at different points of this app for the styling
- I also made use of external libraries for the icons I used on this project

# **Personal Projects**

Built a YouTube clone app with functionalities like YouTube. Implemented some features to not make the website just bare. Implemented with the help of an API, real time information

- I used React JS and Material UI for the main part of this project
- The videos displayed are real time videos gotten from a YouTube API from Rapid API website
- Axios was used for the API calls
- The project follows good folder practices with well-structured and ordered folders and files
- I also used best React practices and concepts like useState, useEffects, react-router etc. during this project This project is fully responsive on basically all devices

## React Developer - Crypto Info

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Main tools used - React JS, API, Axios, Millify

This is a web app built with React JS to display real time information about cryptocurrencies.

All the information are real time crypto information and news gotten from an API

- I used Axios to make the API requests
- I de-structured the results from the API and passed them as contacts to finally use them as props before dynamically displaying them
- I used lots of state management in this project to manage this App
- I used Ant design for the styling of this project
- I also used some external libraries like Millify which I used to write the numbers in readable and easy to understand format

### **Education**

**Bachelor of Science (Ed) in Mathematics Education** University of Lagos **CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript** Harvard X

### Skills

JavaScript – React JS – Next JS – Vue JS – Context API – Redux – Sanity – Axios – Firebase – Material UI – Tailwind CSS – FlowBite – Bootstrap – SASS/SCSS – API – WordPress – WooCommerce – VS Code – JSON – jQuery – Responsive Design – Python/Django – REST API – Testing and Debugging – SCRUM/AGILE – External CSS Libraries – External React Libraries